A Guide to the Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Deputy Chief of Staff Matt Conrad, Records, 2011-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Deputy Chief of Staff Matt Conrad, Records 2011-2013
The Library of Virginia
51145
1 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per code of Virginia 42.1-78. Restricted records in this collection have been sealed but not removed from the collection. Types of sealed information may include, but are not limited to: social security numbers, fingerprints, and other Department of Corrections inmate material. It may be necessary for reference archivist to review any records that may contain additional confidential information that has not been identified and sealed before records can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies of records can be made for patrons to use
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 51145 transferred on 9 January 2014.
Biographical Information
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor, Chief of Staff, Counselor to the Governor and their assistants. The Chief of Staff is the chief operating officer of state government, responsible for all aspects of service to citizens. The Chief oversees the Cabinet members and agency heads in the administration of state government and is also responsible for the operations of the Governor's Office and is assisted in these responsibilities by a Deputy Chief of Staff.
Governor Robert F. McDonnell appointed Matthew A. Conrad as his first Deputy Chief of Staff in June 2011. This position provided support for Chief of Staff Martin Kent. Conrad had served as Deputy Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry, helping run two state agencies. Prior to serving on his gubernatorial staff, Conrad worked with McDonnell in the Attorney General’s Office, as a special assistant U.S. Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia and at the Richmond-based Alliance Group,where he was the founding director of the Virginia Wine Council in 2008. As part of the McDonnell administration’s government reform efforts, Conrad worked to streamline and enhance the operations of the executive branch until. He served until October 2013, after which he was named Director of Virginia Commonwealth University's Office of Government Relations.
Scope and Content
The Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Executive Office-Deputy Chief of Staff Matt Conrad, Records are housed in 3 boxes. The collection is comprised of working papers of the Deputy Chief of Staff which include memorandums, agendas, email communications, legal and non legal briefings, legal documents, correspondence, reports and proposals.
The Deputy Chief of Staff working Papgers make use of a significant amount of acronyms. The following list, while not comprehensive, represents the majority of acronyms used:
ABC=Alcohol Beverage Control Authority
AG=Attorney General
FERC=Federal Energy Regulatory Commission
MWAA=Metropolitan Washington Airport Authority
FERC=Federal Energy Regulatory Commission
NGA=National Governors Association
LAC=Legal Affairs Committee
PPACA=Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act
PPEA=Public-Private Education Facilities and Infrastructre Act
PPTA=Public-Private Transportation Act
RGPPC=Republican Governors Public Policy Committee
VRS=Virginia Retirement System
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by title.
Related Material
The Governor Robert F. McDonnell Administration Web Archive Collection, 2010-2014 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Maureen McDonnell), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Ken Cuccinelli).
Contents List
- Records of Deputy Chief of Staff Matt Conrad, 2011-2013.
  - ABC Privatization 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Asian Advisory Board 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AG-Robert Charles Gleason 2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AG-Jonathan Christopher Montgomery 2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AG-Tyrone White 2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Council on Virginia's Future 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dept. of Corrections 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dept. of Taxation-Sprint PCS 2012 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Earthquake 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Economic Versatility Task Force Executive Order 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Employment Commission 2013 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - FERC 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - First Lady 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Fort Monroe 2011 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gardiner Tax Case 2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hurricane Briefing 2011 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jozef Pieter de Vries 2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Inspector General 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Land Conservation Foundation 2013 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - MWAA 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MWAA 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NGA-LAC 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - North Anna Power Station 2011 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Office Building Project 2012 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - PPACA-29 Hour Rule 2013 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - PPEA Proposals 2011 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Port PPTA 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Records/Archive Policy 2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reperation/Tax 2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Republican Governors Association 2011 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - RGPPC-Healthcare Amicus 2012 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Supreme Court-Executive Secretary 2011 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Uncategorized Working Papers 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - VRS Op-Ed 2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)